# PAVAN KARTHIK RAMAPURAM

Denton, TX | PavanKarthikRamapuram@my.unt.edu | +1 (940)-758-3075 | LinkedIn

### **EDUCATION**

#### University of North Texas, Denton, TX

Jan 2023 - Dec 2024

Master of Science in Data Science

Relevant Coursework: Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), Data Visualization, Data Analytics

## RMD Engineering College, Tamil Nadu, India

Aug 2015 - Apr 2019

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Relevant Coursework: Circuit Analysis, Digital Electronics, Signals and Systems, Power Systems, Electrical Machines, Programming

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

**Experience:** 3.3 years as a Software Development Engineer in **LTIMindtree** 

**Programming Languages:** JavaScript, React, Python, Java, HTML, CSS, SQL, PowerShell **Technologies and Tools:** Git, Jira, ARAS, Eclipse IDE, Postman, VS Code, Pipelines

Methodologies: Scrum, Agile, Test-Driven Development, Pair Programming, Code Reviews

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Automation Engineer, LTIMindtree, Bangalore, India

Dec 2021 - Dec 2022

- Collaborated with a 20-member cross-functional (product, engineering, support) team, serving 10,000+ users, releasing weekly updates by checking with business requirements, on a codebase with 200,000 lines of code.
- Revamped an 8-hour manual system check process, saving clients 8 hours daily by eliminating their wait and dependency on manual checks for system restoration which saved 90%. Led the project single-handedly.

Technologies and Tools: PowerShell, VS Code, Azure

## Senior Software Engineer, LTIMindtree, Bangalore, India

May 2021 - Dec 2021

- It's an Inventory management system that works on ARAS PLM. Led the project single-handedly.
- Improved and developed features for tracking blades, hardware goods transportation, and logistics management.
- Revamped UI using React, resulting in a 15% uptick in customer usage and engagement, driving higher customersatisfaction

Technologies and Tools: React, JS, HTML, ARAS, VS Code

# Software Engineer, LTIMindtree, Bangalore, India

Dec 2020 - May 2021

- Created a Login Page Module, earning a 9.5/10 endorsement from the CEO and CTO, serving as the primary gateway to the application. It's an E-Commerce site where tooth products are being sold.
- Developed features for the application and created a new landing page to smoothen customer experience.
- Customized the features of Product Display, Association, Categorization, and styling. Mainly designed for two types of users B2C and B2B.

Technologies and Tools: HTML, CSS, JS, ReactJS, VS Code, BigCommerce

# Software Engineer, LTIMindtree, Bangalore, India

Jan 2020 - Nov 2020

- Engineered seamless data flows by leveraging APIs to power dynamic beauty-focused e-commerce functionalities, enhancing user experience and platform efficiency.
- Consumed APIs for customizing various parts of applications like Products, and enhancing content.
- Customized Product Display, Association, and Categorization features for two types of users B2C and B2B, boosting user engagement by 20% and simplifying navigation across the platform.

Technologies and Tools: HTML, CSS, JS, ReactJS, VS Code, BigCommerce

### **INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE**

# Intern, LTIMindtree, India

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

- Created a bus ticket booking system backend application using Spring Boot Microservices as a framework and MySQL as DBMS.
- Created multiple services like User System, Ticket System, and Location System and connected them using EUREKA and hosted them separately as Individual services. Tested the APIs using POSTMAN and SWAGGER UI

Technologies and Tools: Java, Spring Boot, JPA, JDBC, MySQL, EUREKA, SWAGGER UI, Eclipse IDE.

# **AWARDS**

- Secured A1 team award consecutively three times as the best performer of the team in my work experience.
- Secured Mastermind award for re-designing the UI of the automated mail system in my work experience.